OGUNDERO MICHEAL AYODEJI

+2348087365099 | ogunderomicheal@yahoo.com | Mushin, Lagos, Nigeria

PROFILE SUMMARY

Experienced and top-performing IT professional with over 7 years of experience in software engineering, development, programming, quality assurance, support and implementation in the ecommerce and fintech industries. Excel in designing and developing intuitive full-stack enterprise web applications, applying solid design principles and software design patterns across multiple technology stacks. Deep programming language knowledge with working knowledge of the general mobile landscape, architectures, trends, and emerging technologies; solid understanding of the full mobile development life cycle; critical thinker and problem-solving skills.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Web & SoftwareDevelopment
- Programming Languages
- SDLC Project Delivery
- Applications Architecture
- User Requirements

- IT Risk Assessment
- Quality Assurance
- System Migration & Integration
- Technical Architecture Design
- System Integration & Testing
- Access Management
- Data Interpretation
- Instrumentation & Control Systems

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer - Syarpa., UK / Nigeria

Jan. 2022 - Present

- Handles payments processes (both crypto and fiat) on the platform.
- Builds the microservice to manually manage exchange rates on the website with NodeJS/NestJS framework.
- Documents and demonstrates solutions by developing documentation, flowcharts, layouts, diagrams, charts, code comments and clear code.
- Prepares and installs solutions by determining and designing system specifications, standards and programming.
- Designs and updates software using collected data, systems analysis and prior bug reports; confers with management teams regarding user reports to personalize software and increase productivity.

Software Engineer - The Bulb Africa

May. 2021 - Dec. 2021

- Implemented signalR and Redis to effectively handle real-time communication between the backend-service and the mobile app.
- Handled bill payments, airtime and data recharge integrations with different service providers.
- Developed the settl.me USSD application that allows users to create account, pay bills, buy airtime, request money, transfer money and perform some other functions via a USSD channel.
- Tracked, documented, and maintained software and network system functionality—both internally and externally, leveraging opportunities to improve engineering productivity.
- Engaged in software testing to identify defects early in the development process and ensure quality assurance.

Contract Software Engineer - Syarpa., UK / Nigeria

Feb. 2021 - Jul. 2021

- Managed and spearheaded all OTP requests and validation processes for login, transactions and two-FA.
- Worked with Coinbase API and AbokiFx API to fetch current exchange rates and also integrated Stripe and Circle APIs to handle payout to customers.
- Involved in the authentication, identification and documentation of verification processes and implemented integrations with Flutterwave & Loqate for Nigeria and UK accounts validation respectively.
- Developed key components to support identity, authentication, and mobile engagement features.
- Maintained a stable server with zero downtime.

Contract Software Engineer - Polaris Bank Ltd

Dec. 2020 - Mar. 2021

- Refactored some processes between Polaris bank and NIBBS for inward and outward transfers to the bank.
- Assessed customer and internal project requirements to execute new accessories and modify all existing solutions.
- Maintained knowledge of technologies which cover API specification, Financial Information Exchange and latest developments.
- Ensured optimal knowledge on all bank trading process and ensure speedy development and reliable service and acceleration of product quality.

Software Engineering Consultant – "Cervitech" Mobile Application

Apr. 2019 - Feb. 2020

- Implemented FCM push notification feature.
- Supervised and managed other software developers and also worked as the lead backend developer.
- Wrote technical specifications and maintained all reports about application development processes.
- Participated in the complete Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) for development, testing, and code enhancement.
- Worked with team members to gain further platform understandings and debugging.

Software Engineer - Information Technology Department, Wallets. Africa

Dec. 2017 - Apr. 2018

- Co-designed the database architecture and also built backend services that handle user managements and payment transactions.
- Integrated different payment gateways like Quickteller and Flutterwave on the platform to process payment.
- Implemented Barter Cards services to manage virtual dollar cards for consumers.
- Handled deployment of services on Microsoft azure machines.

Software Engineer - Information Technology Department, Wallets. Africa

Jan. 2015 - May 2017

2019

- Ensured the best possible performance, quality, and responsiveness of applications.
- Identified bottlenecks and bugs, and devised swift solutions to these problems.

M.Sc. Artificial Intelligence (Merit) - University of Lagos Akoka Nigeria

- Translated product documents and sprints into functional applications.
- Authored technical documentation to assist other developers in understanding the implemented application architecture and design methods.

EDUCATION

•	B.Sc. Systems Engineering (First Class) – University of Lagos, Akoka	2015
0.5		
CE	RTIFICATIONS	
•	Data Structures & Algorithms, JavaScript, Udemy	2022
•	Serverless Framework Bootcamp: Node.js, AWS & Microservices, Udemy	2022
•	NestJS Zero to Hero, Modern TypeScript Backend Development, Udemy	2021
•	Dynamic User Experience: Ajax Design and Usability, Interaction Design Foundation	2016
•	Grade 5 Music Theory, Associated Board of the Royal Schools of Music, London (ABRSM)	2015

TECHNICAL SKILLS

•	C#	•	JQuery	•	Git
•	ASP.NET CORE	•	HTML	•	AWS
•	ASP.NET MVC,	•	CSS	•	Docker
•	NodeJS	•	MSSQL	•	CI/CD
•	NestJS JavaScript	•	MongoDB	•	Serverless Framework
•	Python	•	PostgreSQL		

PORTFOLIO

- Settl.me (https://settl.me/) is a platform that provides financial services for people within community at affordable rates.
- CerviTech (https://www.cervitech.com.ng/) is a mobile application that monitors neck posture with smart phones.
- SureGifts (https://suregifts.co.ke/) is a platform for buying gift cards, egift cards & vouchers for birthdays, Christmas, valentine etc.
- SureGifts Business (https://business.suregifts.com.ng/) A platform for corporate gift cards, rewards and loyalty for businesses.
- SureRemit (https://sureremit.co/) A platform for sending voucher, paying bills, mobile airtime top-up etc.